Face your demons.
Beowulf is a adventure, action, animation film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
A 6th-century Scandinavian warrior named Beowulf embarks on a
mission to slay the man-like ogre, Grendel.
Beowulf / Golden Man / Dragon, played by Ray Winstone.
Grendel's Mother, played by Angelina Jolie.
Hrothgar, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Unferth, played by John Malkovich.
Wealthow, played by Robin Wright.
Wiglaf, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Beowulf is a 2007 American animated fantasy action film produced and directed by Robert Zemeckis, written by Neil Gaiman and Roger Avary, based on the Old English epic poem
Beowulf, and featuring the voices of Ray Winstone, Anthony Hopkins, Robin Wright, Brendan Gleeson, John Malkovich, Crispin Glover, Alison Lohman, and Angelina Jolie.
The film depicts a modern interpretation of the poem, with
certain changes to aspects of its story.
It was produced by Shangri-La Entertainment and Zemeckis's ImageMovers and features characters animated using
motion-capture animation, which was previously used in The Polar Express (2004) and Monster House (2006).
Beowulf premiered at Westwood, Los Angeles on November 5, 2007, and was released theatrically in
the United States on November 16, 2007, by Paramount Pictures, with Warner Bros.
Pictures handling international distribution.
It grossed $196.4 million and was generally well received by critics, though
there was criticism towards its deviations from the original poem.
The film explores themes of denmark, lie, pride and
vanity, folk hero, vikings (norsemen).